<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Nutritional Balancing &#8211; Hair Diagnostics</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/nutritional-balancing/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Hair Diagnostics</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 18:57:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Why Positive Thinking and Self-Help Books are Getting You Nowhere</title>
		<link>/2015/10/20/why-positive-thinking-and-self-help-books-are-getting-you-nowhere/</link>
					<comments>/2015/10/20/why-positive-thinking-and-self-help-books-are-getting-you-nowhere/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hair Diagnostics]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 18:10:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Nutritional Balancing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.hairdiagnostics.com/?p=2168</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The self-help industry has been booming over the past decade, earning millions of pounds in the UK and many billions of dollars across the pond. Yet whilst our bookshelves are positively brimming with purchases, what more do we have to...<br /><a class="moretag" href="/2015/10/20/why-positive-thinking-and-self-help-books-are-getting-you-nowhere/">Read the full article &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2015/10/20/why-positive-thinking-and-self-help-books-are-getting-you-nowhere/">Why Positive Thinking and Self-Help Books are Getting You Nowhere</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Hair Diagnostics</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>The self-help industry has been booming</strong> over the past decade, earning millions of pounds in the UK and many billions of dollars across the pond. Yet whilst our bookshelves are positively brimming with purchases, what more do we have to show for these words of wisdom? Where is the promised wave of success stories and fairy tale endings?</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.hairdiagnostics.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/Bookshelves.jpg" alt="Bookshelves" width="100%" height="401" class="alignnone fullwidth-img wp-image-2192" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/Bookshelves.jpg 4896w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/10/Bookshelves-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/10/Bookshelves-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 4896px) 100vw, 4896px" /></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span class="emp">Original Article: <i><strong><a href="http://arltma.com/Articles/PosThinkDoc.htm">Positive Thinking &#8211; A Biological Concept</a></strong></i>, Analytical Research Labs, Inc.</span></p>
<h3>Introduction</h3>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>Many of us wish we were the person that we are not.</strong> If we do not feel that we are adequate in our jobs or as successful as we think we should be, we may turn to books and techniques to help us become more accomplished. These techniques may take the form of reading positive thinking books, self-improvement courses, or meditation. We may even develop a lifestyle based on the philosophy of a guru or self-proclaimed individual who teaches the way to a better life rests in following in his footsteps. This guru will proselytise the type of lifestyle and habits that he is comfortable with. What many of us do not realise is that none of the success books teach us how to become a success, but only tell how a particular individual made his fortune or became a financial wizard.</span></p>
<h3>Success and Achievement is Achieved Through<br />
the Ability to Accumulate Excess Energy</h3>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">We may not realise that what our idol has achieved, so can we, <strong>not by following in his footsteps</strong>, but by relying on our own inborn abilities. This ability to be positive, to be optimistic, to be successful, to be who we really desire to be, does not rest in following someone&#8217;s technique, but by having the energy to generate creative thoughts and then having sufficient excess energy to carry those ideas through to completion.</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone fullwidth-img wp-image-2198" style="margin-left: 2em; float: right;" src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/balance.jpeg" alt=“balance" width="212" height="318" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/balance.jpeg 3456w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/10/balance-200x300.jpeg 200w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/10/balance-683x1024.jpeg 683w" sizes="(max-width: 212px) 100vw, 212px" /><br />
<span style="font-size: 18pt; color: #28a9e0"><strong class ="light">Energy is Achieved Through a Balanced Body Chemistry</strong></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">To feel inspired to achieve, one&#8217;s body chemistry must be balanced. The condition of one&#8217;s adrenal and thyroid gland can be a main deciding factor between prosperity and poverty. If one&#8217;s adrenal gland is weak and his thyroid gland is underactive, (inability to generate energy), one simply does not have the physical motivation to actively pursue goals. This glandular exhaustion also affects attitude, as one cannot feel positive when the body does not have sufficient energy to pursue simple tasks.</span></p>
<h3>Physical Health and Propensity Towards<br />
Achievement Have a Significant Correlation</h3>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Physical health and propensity towards achievement have a significant correlation. For example, an extreme slow oxidiser, with a hypothyroid and hypoadrenal gland, is in a state of psychological withdrawal. <strong>This withdrawal is the body&#8217;s protective mechanism with which to conserve energy.</strong> Introversion is a result of energy conservation. To be extroverted, one must have excess available energy with which to create expression. The extreme slow oxidiser is simply too low key to make his positive feelings visible.</span></p>
<h3>The Extremely Fast-Fast Oxidiser</h3>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The extreme fast oxidiser, with his hyperactive adrenal glands and hyperactive thyroid gland, fluctuates between extroversion and introversion. When the fast oxidiser reaches extreme states of oxidation, the adrenal and thyroid burn out temporarily and become insufficient, due to continual stress. Stress creates a personality that is outgoing and even hyperactive one day, and totally exhausted and depressed the next day. The resultant personality characteristics appear inconsistent and disorganised.</span></p>
<h3>The Mixed Oxidiser</h3>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The mixed oxidiser will have similar characteristics to the extreme fast oxidiser, however the extreme highs and lows will be modified. The confusion and disorganisation may be even more obvious.</span></p>
<h3>The Moderately Fast-Fast Oxidiser</h3>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The moderately fast oxidiser (what is referred to as normal), tends to be energetic; positive in his thinking, attitudes, emotions and outgoing. These are usually very successful people, as they have the energy to be expressive and consistent in their effort to achieve.</span></p>
<h3 class="emp"><em>&#8220;It is not self-help books that will motivate one to success but proper body chemistry.&#8221;</em></h3>
<h3>You Are The World</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone fullwidth-img wp-image-2209" style="margin-left: 2em; float: right;" src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/Planet.jpg" alt=“Planet" width="240" height="232" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/Planet.jpg 1056w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/10/Planet-300x290.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/10/Planet-1024x989.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 240px) 100vw, 240px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The quotation, &#8220;You are the world,&#8221; is significant to consider. What does it really mean? <strong>Whatever we are, within ourselves, is how we see the world outside. Our world changes according to the changes that occur within us.</strong> The world, in actuality, remains the same, but what we see as individuals is dependent upon our state of mind, which is in itself, dependent upon our body chemistry, which is different for everyone. One moment we look at the world as being something really joyful, because our chemistry is in balance. Other times, even though we are in the same situation or environment, we see life as bleak and we may even be very depressed. This depression may be due to our copper level rising, or a sodium to potassium inversion (sodium/potassium ratio less than 2.5:1) or heavy metal accumulation in the liver and brain.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Environmental contaminants, junk food and negative emotions effect our chemistry negatively. Also, positive emotions, nutritional foods, a naturing environment and exercise affect our chemistry and resultant personality.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">There are presently a number of fad products in the health food industry, touted as being beneficial for everyone. They include spirula, brewers yeast, green magma, S.O.D., etc. <strong>Each of these products are good for some people</strong>, however if an individual is a fast oxidiser with a sodium to potassium inversion takes Brewer&#8217;s yeast, he may become anxiety ridden, paranoid and confused. The wonder food yeast can be quite harmful to him because over a period of time it can cause a loss of calcium and magnesium, the very minerals that fast oxidisers are deficient in.</span></p>
<h3>The Psychological Effects Of Foods On The Emotions</h3>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Foods have a profound effect on the emotions. We all know that the drinking or eating of refined carbohydrates such as pop, candy, cake, ice cream, chocolate, etc., will give us a quick energy lift. However, the resultant physical and emotional letdown afterward is certainly not worth the price which we eventually are forced to pay.</span></p>
<h3>Even Nutritious Foods Can Serve as the<br />
&#8216;Straw That Breaks the Camel&#8217;s Back&#8217;</h3>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Often, foods we think of as nutritious, such as soybeans, avocados, walnuts and almonds, can create depression and fatigue in individuals with excessive copper in their tissues. This is because the aforementioned foods are rich in copper. When eaten in even small amounts they may serve as &#8216;the straw that breaks the camel&#8217;s back&#8217;.</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.hairdiagnostics.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/Avocados.jpg" alt="Avocados" width="100%" height="403" class="alignnone fullwidth-img wp-image-2225" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/Avocados.jpg 3736w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/10/Avocados-300x201.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/10/Avocados-1024x685.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 3736px) 100vw, 3736px" /></p>
<h3>The Foods One Eats Should Relate to<br />
One&#8217;s Individual Body Chemistry</h3>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">It is not that a food is generally nutritious that is most important, but how that particular food relates to one&#8217;s individual biochemistry. A slow oxidiser with a sodium to potassium greater than 2.5:1 may get an energy lift from the addition of pure brewers yeast, contributing to his feelings of self confidence.</span></p>
<h3>The Effects Of Positive Emotions On Our Body Chemistry</h3>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Not only food, but positive emotions can have a significant effect on our body chemistry. Love, for example, can change one&#8217;s complete perception of the world.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">There is an old saying, &#8220;Love changes the world.&#8221; Love can actually change one&#8217;s chemistry to where one views life as being beautiful. Whenever a person falls in love, they usually feel really good. They start noticing things that they haven&#8217;t noticed before, such as landscapes, trees, the stars, the sky, and nature in general. We begin seeing things that we haven&#8217;t noticed before or develop feelings for them, because love awakens our emotions. The whole world appears to change, but actually it&#8217;s still the same. Insofar as one can love, the world becomes increasingly beautiful. The world can seem to change outside us, but the changes are actually occurring within us. Loving feelings simply put us more in touch with our inner selves.</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.hairdiagnostics.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/Family.jpg" alt="Family" width="100%" height="403" class="alignnone fullwidth-img wp-image-2251" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/Family.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/10/Family-300x200.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">An example of how love can make a change in a person is the story of a woman who bought a novel. She read the first chapter and found it very boring and uninteresting and put it aside. Years later she met the author and later married him. She picked up the book again with renewed interest and found it so interesting that she read it a number of times. What really changed? The content of the book remained the same over the years, but her perception of it changed.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In terms of specifics how love affects biochemistry, we have viewed people with severe sodium to potassium inversions normalise their sodium to potassium ratio through love. We have seen arteriosclerosis, arthritis and allergy patients rid themselves of symptoms as their body chemistry approached normalcy.</span></p>
<h3 class="emp"><em>&#8220;Emotions: good or bad have a tremendous effect on the status of our health.&#8221;</em></h3>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The point is emotions, good or bad, have a tremendous effect on our health!</span></p>
<h3>Many Roads to the Desired Goal</h3>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">There is only one type of positive mental attitude, optimism, living in the present, but there are a number of roads which lead to the desired goal. An individual with a severe energy loss, whether they are aware of it or not, depending upon severity and chronicity, may be in a state of extreme pretence, trying to act as though they are OK. Pretence is a state of acting. There are many techniques of learning positive thinking to help us pretend that we are positive. <strong>Some techniques suggest replacing negative thoughts by what is thought of as positive thoughts. This, of course, is only reinforcing the negativity.</strong> As long as our energy holds out, we may put on a good show for a while. How lonely this is, not to be able to share our true feelings with anyone. Putting up a front of being positive no matter how bad we really feel is a tremendous drain on our already low energy levels. In this predicament, we may feel destined never to let anyone really know us, thus never really getting to know anyone, or share this thing called life with them. The only thing we can share with another person in this state of pretence is our techniques that we have learned to unknowingly fool everyone else.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">There is a saying, &#8220;To thine own self be true.&#8221; If you are going through this type of technique use and fooling everyone around you, at least try to be honest with yourself so that you can do something positive about it. Otherwise, you will eventually become so exhausted from pretence that you will not be able to keep up the front anyway. This condition of pretence is usually associated with slow oxidation, although it also frequently occurs in the fast oxidiser with a sodium to potassium inversion. Nobody is totally immune.</span></p>
<h3>The Achilles Heel Of The Fast Oxidiser</h3>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Another type of individual, the extreme fast oxidiser, may have sufficient energy to be creative, ambitious and successful. As a rule he does not follow anyone&#8217;s ideas but his own. He is individual in his thinking, and yet with all these things going for him, he too frequently fails in his attempt to live a healthy, successful, happy life. His frequent lack of ability, due to impending <a href="http://www.hairdiagnostics.com/medical-conditions/adrenal-burnout/">adrenal burnout</a>, to be able to carry through with those ideas is the fear of failing. His energy is not directed, but is spent in many different directions at once. This is actually a technique for him. By having several different things going for him at once, he has an excuse of never completing or accomplishing, he is withdrawing or repressing his real ability, due to the distorted and unrealistic fear of failure. Again, &#8220;To thine own self be true.&#8221; Instead of using a technique, the basic fear should be evaluated and dealt with. To be able to recognise fear and to deal adequately with it, one must have a high energy level. A high energy level provides one with stability. Stability fosters guidance and perseverance, qualities the fast oxidiser so often lacks. He can become very successful once stabilised.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">What we have been discussing is our ability to achieve and to be positive thinkers. In our opinion this ability rests on our internal biochemistry. Our chemistry can be changed, first by asking ourselves, &#8220;Do we want to be more than we are? Do we want to be all we can be, and be positive about ourselves and the world we live in?&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">What we have been discussing is biochemical individuality, as recognised from a <a href="http://www.hairdiagnostics.com/how-it-works/hair-tissue-mineral-analysis/">Hair Tissue Mineral Analysis</a>. The extreme slow oxidiser is on the inside looking out, so to speak. Always trying but never quite succeeding because he is often aware that he won&#8217;t succeed based on past experiences of failure. The extreme fast oxidiser is on the outside but never strikes out on the journey and represses his true ability due to a fear of failure, confusion and disorganisation.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Before we read another self-help book, perhaps we should have our chemistry analysed to see why we think we need help.</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.hairdiagnostics.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/Open-Book.jpg" alt="Open Book" width="100%" height="223" class="alignnone fullwidth-img wp-image-2228" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/Open-Book.jpg 4855w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/10/Open-Book-300x111.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/10/Open-Book-1024x380.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 4855px) 100vw, 4855px" /></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2015/10/20/why-positive-thinking-and-self-help-books-are-getting-you-nowhere/">Why Positive Thinking and Self-Help Books are Getting You Nowhere</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Hair Diagnostics</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2015/10/20/why-positive-thinking-and-self-help-books-are-getting-you-nowhere/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What is Nutritional Balancing?</title>
		<link>/2015/09/10/what-is-nutritional-balancing/</link>
					<comments>/2015/09/10/what-is-nutritional-balancing/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hair Diagnostics]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 11:05:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Nutritional Balancing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.hairdiagnostics.com/?p=1350</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;This programme may not appeal initially to the faint hearted – it does require perseverance – but if one acknowledges the deep-seated cries for help from an exhausted body, that perseverance will be highly rewarded.&#8221; Ron C. Australia Today within...<br /><a class="moretag" href="/2015/09/10/what-is-nutritional-balancing/">Read the full article &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2015/09/10/what-is-nutritional-balancing/">What is Nutritional Balancing?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Hair Diagnostics</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3><span style="font-size: 14pt;"><i>&#8220;This programme may not appeal initially to the faint hearted – it does require perseverance – but if one acknowledges the deep-seated cries for help from an exhausted body, that perseverance will be highly rewarded.&#8221;</i> <span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>Ron C. Australia</strong></span></span></h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone mobile-center wp-image-539 " style="margin-right: 2em; float: left;" src="http://www.hairdiagnostics.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/nutritional-large-icon.png" alt="" width="179" height="155" /></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>Today</strong> within everyone&#8217;s family unit, most of us will be affected by a frightening and debilitating health condition. Despite substantial pharmaceutical investment and claims of drug-based progress, degenerative diseases such as Alzheimer&#8217;s and Parkinson&#8217;s, the metabolic disorders, diabetes and obesity, and neurological distress including autism and epilepsy are now endemic. Constant low energy, digestive weakness and regular infections are now accepted as normal. The limitations of a drug and surgery based medicine are becoming painfully clear as today, it is rare to die peacefully of old age.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Nutritional Balancing Science, aided by <a href="http://www.hairdiagnostics.com/how-it-works/hair-tissue-mineral-analysis/">Hair Tissue Mineral Analysis</a>, identifies and addresses the real cause of disease: biochemical stress. Stress from diet. Stress from nutritional deficiencies. Stress from toxicity, from attitudes and relationships. <strong>Stress has become a lifestyle in itself.</strong> Whilst a medical label identifies the geography of these biochemical stresses, over the counter prescriptions will not address their cause. We are not deficient in drugs, we are deficient in nutrients and overflowing with toxicity.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Rather than targeting the symptoms of stress, Nutritional Balancing directly addresses the causes of and physical response to that stress.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span class="emp" style="color: #368eca; font-size: 12pt;">Results can be quick, but the real beauty is that<br />
the programme moves far beyond a disease free body.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">As nutrients are replenished, toxicities eliminated, and hidden infections resolved, we are powerfully challenged to re-evaluate the beliefs, attitudes and expectations that stand as overwhelming obstacles to our health. Under these conditions, <strong>health becomes a vibrant, grounded sense of self</strong>, measured not just by biochemical parameters, but by it’s strength of calmness, kindness, compassion and understanding.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Any health programme aiming this high needs to be dynamic and all-encompassing.</span><br />
<span style="font-size: 10pt;"> Nutritional Balancing is both:</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>Dynamic</strong> in that it adapts to the ever changing nutrient needs of a body detoxifying and regenerating.</span></li>
<p></p>
<li><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>All-encompassing</strong> in that its methods address all types of stress, symptom, detoxification and regeneration.<br />
</span></li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span class="emp" style="color: #368eca; font-size: 12pt;">Support is fundamental and for this reason,<strong><br />
full, unlimited guidance is at the core of our service</strong>.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">As you advance through your Nutritional Balancing programme, we will smooth the bumps, soften the corners, steady the downhills and encourage the ups. Parents and children particularly thrive in this process.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">To learn more, please browse our website or <a href="https://calendly.com/hairdiagnostics/" target="_blank"><span class="s3">book a free consultation</a>. Alternatively, to start the journey of a lifetime, <a title="Order Your Analysis" href="/order-your-analysis/">order your hair analysis</a> today.</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2015/09/10/what-is-nutritional-balancing/">What is Nutritional Balancing?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Hair Diagnostics</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2015/09/10/what-is-nutritional-balancing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
